<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <atom:link href="https://pacercms.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <link>https://pacercms.github.io/</link>
    <description></description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 23:00:39 -0500</pubDate>
    
      <item>
        <title>PacerCMS no longer in active development</title>
        <link>https://pacercms.github.io/index.php/2010/01/03/pacercms-no-longer-in-active-development/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://pacercms.github.io/index.php/2010/01/03/pacercms-no-longer-in-active-development/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As often is the case with open-source projects, there is a period of initial work by a single developer and a collaborative period among other developers and contributors as interest grows. What happens after that separates the software that many of us have adopted as part of our daily lives (WordPress, Drupal, Firefox, etc.) from those that have quietly faded from our minds. Today, PacerCMS is moving into that second category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As over year has passed since the last code commit, PacerCMS is a dormant project.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project has its roots in a personal need of mine: none of the current CMS platforms could adapt to the workflow that I needed at my college newspaper. The workflow itself was simple: multiple users could contribute content to an &quot;Issue&quot;, and at an administrator could publish all of the content in that issue at once by just changing a setting. Certain contributors could only work on content in their &quot;Section&quot; and it could be restricted to only the current or next &quot;Issue.&quot; Even today, few CMS packages can do that out of the box. But then again, perhaps the workflow was not the most ideal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything on the site will continue to be available for as long as &lt;a href=&quot;http://sourceforge.net/projects/pacercms/&quot;&gt;SourceForge&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/pacercms/&quot;&gt;Google Code&lt;/a&gt; keep it around. If you find something useful in the source code for your own project, it has always been there for the taking. If you have an active open source project that better suits the needs of college/community newspapers and magazines, &lt;a href=&quot;http://stephenyeargin.com/contact&quot;&gt;let me know&lt;/a&gt; and I will happily direct visitors to your site.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2010 16:04:07 -0600</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>PacerCMS 0.7.1 Released</title>
        <link>https://pacercms.github.io/index.php/2008/08/31/pacercms-071-released/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://pacercms.github.io/index.php/2008/08/31/pacercms-071-released/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Labor Day marks the ceremonial end of summer, and that means that most student publications are kicking back into high gear. We extend a special welcome to new staff members and wish you a successful year! PacerCMS has a maintenance release available, primarily addressing an issue within the Section Manager that was preventing the creation of new sections. There are a few other minor tweaks here and there throughout the codebase to improve performance and reliability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;This Release (Subversion R139)&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix error when attempting to add sections (#&lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/pacercms/issues/detail?id=26&amp;can=1&quot;&gt;26&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various bug fixes and minor enhancements from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/pacercms-discuss&quot;&gt;Developer&#39;s List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sourceforge.net/project/showfiles.php?group_id=157723&amp;amp;package_id=176431&amp;amp;release_id=623329&quot;&gt;Download PacerCMS 0.7.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2008 17:53:37 -0500</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>PacerCMS 0.7 Released</title>
        <link>https://pacercms.github.io/index.php/2008/04/29/pacercms-07-released/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://pacercms.github.io/index.php/2008/04/29/pacercms-07-released/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The latest stable release of PacerCMS is now available for download. We would like to thank user inner.ground for his fantastic work on developing the internationalization capabilities found in this release, and Eric Lemoine for creating the first localization of PacerCMS in French. This release also introduces a database upgrade tool, which will aide in making sure future updates to PacerCMS run smoothly. Editors can also now &quot;Preview&quot; an issue&#39;s front page, sections and individual articles prior to to setting it as the &quot;current&quot; issue through the issue manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, we invite &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/pacercms-discuss&quot;&gt;feedback&lt;/a&gt; on our software and &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/pacercms-discuss&quot;&gt;suggestions&lt;/a&gt; on how it may be improved. We are also &lt;a href=&quot;http://pacercms.sourceforge.net/index.php/2007/10/13/seeking-developers/&quot;&gt;always seeking developers&lt;/a&gt; to help improve our project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;This Release (Subversion R129)&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Localization (&lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/pacercms/issues/detail?id=22&quot;&gt;#22&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Localization: French (&lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/pacercms/issues/detail?id=24&quot;&gt;#24&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upgrade scripts for installer (&lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/pacercms/issues/detail?id=8&quot;&gt;#8&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Preview Mode&quot; for public side (&lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/pacercms/issues/detail?id=16&quot;&gt;#16&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various bug fixes and minor enhancements from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/pacercms-discuss&quot;&gt;Developer&#39;s List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://prdownloads.sourceforge.net/pacercms/pacercms0.7.zip?download&quot;&gt;Download PacerCMS 0.7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/pacercms-discuss&quot;&gt;Discuss this Release&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2008 20:21:11 -0500</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Localization in PacerCMS</title>
        <link>https://pacercms.github.io/index.php/2008/03/08/localization-in-pacercms/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://pacercms.github.io/index.php/2008/03/08/localization-in-pacercms/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;PacerCMS developer inner.ground has recently completed the integration of an implementation of PHP&#39;s gettext function without the need for complex server configuration. He has also devised a way to extract all of the strings in the default template and throughout the Site Administrator so that they may be translated into countless other languages. We have posted the PO file to the subversion repository, where it will also be released with future versions of PacerCMS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Link:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://pacercms.googlecode.com/svn/trunk/locale/tools/LC_MESSAGES/&quot;&gt;http://pacercms.googlecode.com/svn/trunk/locale/tools/LC_MESSAGES/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a background in a language other than English and would like to be involved in localizing PacerCMS, please &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/pacercms-discuss&quot;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2008 20:19:51 -0600</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Urgent: Remove adodb-perf-module.inc.php from your install</title>
        <link>https://pacercms.github.io/index.php/2008/02/20/urgent-remove-adodb-perf-moduleincphp-from-your-install/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://pacercms.github.io/index.php/2008/02/20/urgent-remove-adodb-perf-moduleincphp-from-your-install/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A vulnerability in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://adodblite.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;ADOdb Lite&lt;/a&gt; package that PacerCMS uses to interact with the database has been discovered that could potentially allow an attacker to execute PHP on your system. Please &lt;strong&gt;remove the following file&lt;/strong&gt; from your install, as its functionality is of limited use to the software at this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;	&lt;tt&gt;./includes/adodb_lite/adodb-perf-module.inc.php&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order for the attacker to exploit your system &lt;tt&gt;register_globals&lt;/tt&gt; would have to be enabled on your PHP installation with your Web host. Most modern hosts have this feature disabled by default, but some (including GoDaddy) leave it enabled for backwards compatibility. Further reading:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;	http://php.net/register_globals&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, please take a moment to remove the specified file from your installations even if you do not have &lt;tt&gt;register_globals&lt;/tt&gt; enabled. The problem has been reported to the developer of ADOdb Lite, but a patched version is not yet available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running an online newspaper or magazine may bring some unwelcome attention from those seeking to exploit vulnerabilities in PacerCMS. We have received a great deal more traffic as of late as a result of our previous vulnerability and a few other minor examples that would effect a very small percentage of Web hosts. With that in mind, realize that your site is always in the crosshairs of an attacker because he or she can draw a great deal of attention by defacing or disabling your Web site. If you come across a site outlining a vulnerability in the software, please let us know (through direct e-mail) so that we may act quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2008 19:55:07 -0600</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>PacerCMS 0.6.2 Patch Released</title>
        <link>https://pacercms.github.io/index.php/2008/02/04/pacercms-062-patch-released/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://pacercms.github.io/index.php/2008/02/04/pacercms-062-patch-released/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There is an issue with 0.6.1 that may cause a minor nuisance when adding or updating items in the database on some hosts. If you recently upgraded, here are the files you need to bring your install current.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt;includes/cm-header.php&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt;siteadmin/article-browse.php&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt;siteadmin/article-edit.php&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt;siteadmin/article-media.php&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt;siteadmin/cm-includes/cm-header.php&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt;siteadmin/issue-browse.php&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt;siteadmin/issue-edit.php&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt;siteadmin/page-edit.php&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt;siteadmin/poll-edit.php&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt;siteadmin/profile.php&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt;siteadmin/section-edit.php&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt;siteadmin/settings.php&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt;siteadmin/staff-access.php&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt;siteadmin/staff-edit.php&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt;siteadmin/submitted-browse.php&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt;siteadmin/submitted-edit.php&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;This Release (Subversion R104):&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixes an evaluation error on many hosts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plugs a minor file include risk if configuration file is missing&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/index.php/download/&quot;&gt;Download PacerCMS 0.6.2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2008 19:46:51 -0600</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>PacerCMS 0.6.1 Streamlines Code Base, Addresses Security Issue</title>
        <link>https://pacercms.github.io/index.php/2008/01/21/pacercms-061-streamlines-code-base-addresses-security-issue/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://pacercms.github.io/index.php/2008/01/21/pacercms-061-streamlines-code-base-addresses-security-issue/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We are proud to announce the next release of PacerCMS, 0.6.1. This release is aimed at developers looking to extend the back-end Site Administrator panel by better documentation of the functions and processes that go into publishing stories, managing users and sections. We have also cut down the number of database queries required to do routine tasks through better session management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this version does not add any significant features for the average user other than a few bug fixes, it is recommended for all users. Our friends at RawSecurity.org have outlined a few problems that would allow a malicious visitor to conceivably obtain access rights through &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cross-site_scripting&quot;&gt;cross-site scripting (XSS)&lt;/a&gt; in the content submission public module (&lt;tt&gt;./submit.php&lt;/tt&gt;). Even if you are not able to process a full update right now, please do replace your existing submit.php file with the version found on our &lt;a href=&quot;http://pacercms.googlecode.com/svn/trunk/submit.php&quot;&gt;subversion repositories&lt;/a&gt;. While we cannot guarantee that a site running PacerCMS will be safe from people with malicious intent, we do take security issues seriously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;This Release (R101)&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Streamlined code base in Site Administrator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adoption of phpDoc.org code commenting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security release&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various bug fixes and minor enhancements from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/pacercms-discuss&quot;&gt;Developer&amp;#8217;s List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/index.php/download/&quot;&gt;Download PacerCMS 0.6.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2008 19:34:02 -0600</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Seeking Developers</title>
        <link>https://pacercms.github.io/index.php/2007/10/13/seeking-developers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://pacercms.github.io/index.php/2007/10/13/seeking-developers/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h3&gt;Project Description&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
PacerCMS is an open source adaptation of a PHP/MySQL application used to power a small weekly student newspaper Web site. The package serves as a basic framework for student and non-daily community newspapers. We are currently up to our sixth release of the project, but have not yet reached a stable &quot;1.0&quot; milestone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;General Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Knowledge of basic &lt;a href=&quot;http://subversion.tigris.org/&quot;&gt;Subversion&lt;/a&gt; functions a must in order to contribute to development. Google account (free registration) required &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/pacercms&quot;&gt;to join project on Google Code&lt;/a&gt; (principle location for Subversion repositories). Understanding and appreciation for student and community journalism will aide in catering to our target user base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Areas of Need&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Project&lt;/strong&gt; -- Improve core functionality of project by streamlining activity for collaborative publishing; Review and implement suggestions from the user community; Refactor code base to adhere to a best practices standard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extend Project&lt;/strong&gt; -- Develop a means for a plugin architecture for internal and external development; Create standard API documentation to support plugin architecture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Installation/Upgrading&lt;/strong&gt; -- Set installation requirements for project; Optimize package to be compatible on wide server configurations and user technical skill-sets; Create and maintain a utility to facilitate easy upgrades for future versions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Database&lt;/strong&gt; -- Review database schema and optimize performance; Improve on existing data access layer to add support for more database platforms other than MySQL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Documentation&lt;/strong&gt; -- Create and maintain online documentation for project; Documentation pertains to installation, technical administration and user operation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security&lt;/strong&gt; -- Perform a security audit of the system; identify, review, classify and repair possible security problems; Maintain closed communication with other developers as to protect the installed user base&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;To Inquire&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Please join our discussion list at [&lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/pacercms-discuss&quot;&gt;http://groups.google.com/group/pacercms-discuss&lt;/a&gt;] and post a brief introduction of your interest in the project and skillset. Of course, you will probably wish to &lt;a href=&quot;http://pacercms.sourceforge.net/index.php/download&quot;&gt;download&lt;/a&gt; and install a version of PacerCMS. You will find that our group is cordial, and welcome any ready to contribute. Visit our Web site at [&lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/pacercms-discuss&quot;&gt;http://pacercms.sourceforge.net&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2007 22:10:40 -0500</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>PacerCMS 0.6 Released; Help Wanted</title>
        <link>https://pacercms.github.io/index.php/2007/10/11/pacercms-06-released-help-wanted/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://pacercms.github.io/index.php/2007/10/11/pacercms-06-released-help-wanted/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We are happy to announce the latest stable release of PacerCMS, version 0.6. We thank all of you who provided feedback on our two pre-releases. As the project takes a step closer to 1.0 status, the time has come to renew our call for help from anyone able to contribute back to the code base. Our discussion list stands at more than 20 members, and every day we hear from users about their experiences. Whether your expertise is in design, PHP, javascript, database management, project promotion, language localization or all of the above, we can find a way to get you involved. For more details, simply join the &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/pacercms-discuss&quot;&gt;developer&#39;s list&lt;/a&gt; and introduce yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;This Release (Subversion R87):&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to add and delete sections (&lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/pacercms/issues/detail?id=18&quot;&gt;#18&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Share Article&quot; public module (&lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/pacercms/issues/detail?id=9&quot;&gt;#9&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Themed section pages (&lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/pacercms/issues/detail?id=11&quot;&gt;#11&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various bug fixes and minor enhancements from the Developer&amp;acirc;&amp;euro;&amp;trade;s List&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://prdownloads.sourceforge.net/pacercms/pacercms0.6.zip?download&quot;&gt;Download PacerCMS 0.6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/pacercms-discuss&quot;&gt;Discuss this Release&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2007 19:43:47 -0500</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>PacerCMS 0.6 PR2 Released</title>
        <link>https://pacercms.github.io/index.php/2007/09/28/pacercms-06-pr2-released/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://pacercms.github.io/index.php/2007/09/28/pacercms-06-pr2-released/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The latest preview release is now available for download. This release addresses minor bugs and increase compatibility with certain hosting platforms. This release is the first for our upcoming 0.6 release, which will feature a share article public module, the ability to use themed sections, adding and deleting sections in the Site Administrator, as well as various bug fixes and enhancements from our &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/pacercms-discuss&quot;&gt;PacerCMS Developers list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pacercms.googlecode.com/files/pacercms0.6.PR2.zip&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download PacerCMS 0.6 PR2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2007 21:32:46 -0500</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review: &quot;creating an e-zine -- software choices&quot;</title>
        <link>https://pacercms.github.io/index.php/2007/09/19/review-creating-an-e-zine-software-choices/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://pacercms.github.io/index.php/2007/09/19/review-creating-an-e-zine-software-choices/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Robin, one of our contributors and a frequent help on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/pacercms-discuss&quot;&gt;Developer List&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://contentdivergent.blogspot.com/2007/08/creating-e-zine-software-choices.html&quot;&gt;has written about&lt;/a&gt; some of the software she reviewed on her way to choosing PacerCMS to power &lt;a href=&quot;http://southerncreativity.com&quot;&gt;SouthernCreativity.com&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://southerncreativity.com/moonshine/&quot;&gt;moonshine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; online magazine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2007 18:24:46 -0500</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>PacerCMS 0.6 PR1 Released</title>
        <link>https://pacercms.github.io/index.php/2007/08/18/pacercms-06-pr1-released/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://pacercms.github.io/index.php/2007/08/18/pacercms-06-pr1-released/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The latest preview release is now available for download. This release is the first for our upcoming 0.6 release, which will feature a share article public module, the ability to use themed sections, adding and deleting sections in the Site Administrator, as well as various bug fixes and enhancements from our &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/pacercms-discuss&quot;&gt;PacerCMS Developers list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pacercms.googlecode.com/files/pacercms0.6.PR1.zip&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download PacerCMS 0.6 PR1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2007 09:34:51 -0500</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>PacerCMS 0.5 Released</title>
        <link>https://pacercms.github.io/index.php/2007/02/13/pacercms-05-released/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://pacercms.github.io/index.php/2007/02/13/pacercms-05-released/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, we committed the latest stable version of PacerCMS. Thank you to all those who tried out our Preview Releases and for the much needed feedback. Version 0.5 marks the biggest step forward for the system yet, introducing four great new features that we have highlighted in past entries. We have a growing list of features for 0.6 on our &lt;a href=&quot;http://pacercms.sourceforge.net/index.php/development/&quot;&gt;Development&lt;/a&gt; page, so please take a look and &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/pacercms/issues/list&quot;&gt;add your feature requests&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;This Release (Subversion R65):&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pacercms.sourceforge.net/index.php/2007/02/01/introducing-the-smarty-template-engine/&quot;&gt;The Smarty Template Engine&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/pacercms/issues/detail?id=4&quot;&gt;#4&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pacercms.sourceforge.net/index.php/2007/02/04/introducing-the-new-pacercms-installer/&quot;&gt;No Hassle Installation Script&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/pacercms/issues/detail?id=3&quot;&gt;#3&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pacercms.sourceforge.net/index.php/2007/02/05/introducing-quick-tags-and-flash/&quot;&gt;JavaScript Quick Tags for Articles&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/pacercms/issues/detail?id=6&quot;&gt;#6&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pacercms.sourceforge.net/index.php/2007/02/05/introducing-quick-tags-and-flash/&quot;&gt;Flash Media For Articles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://prdownloads.sourceforge.net/pacercms/pacercms0.5.zip?download&quot;&gt;Download PacerCMS 0.5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/pacercms-discuss&quot;&gt;Discuss this Release&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2007 22:56:42 -0600</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Introducing Quick Tags and Flash</title>
        <link>https://pacercms.github.io/index.php/2007/02/05/introducing-quick-tags-and-flash/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://pacercms.github.io/index.php/2007/02/05/introducing-quick-tags-and-flash/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: This is the final in a three part series leading up to the release of PacerCMS 0.5. You can start building for the upcoming version by &lt;a href=&quot;/index.php/download/&quot;&gt;downloading our preview release&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Simple HTML for the masses&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;float:right;margin-left:10px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://pacercms.sourceforge.net/wp-content/uploads/2007/02/quick_tags.png&quot; alt=&quot;Quick Tags&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;HTML Quick Tags allow users to add formatting without the fuss.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;In addition to our nifty installer, we borrowed another feature from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://wordpress.org/&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; crew (more specifically, &lt;a href=&quot;http://alexking.org/&quot;&gt;Alex King&lt;/a&gt;) in the form of &lt;a href=&quot;http://alexking.org/blog/2004/06/03/js-quicktags-under-lgpl/&quot;&gt;Javascript Quick Tags&lt;/a&gt;. This utility bar appears at the top of of a few places in PacerCMS that accept HTML markup, such as the article and section editors. The way it works is fairly straightforward: You can either select the text you want to format, or click the buttons to insert the opening tag at your cursor position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We culled out a few of the options to leave you with the most basic formatting options for a standard news story. You can now bold, italicize, make lists, insert inline images, create links and set a body of text as a block quote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Now you can bring Flash to your news&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;float:right;margin-left:10px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://pacercms.sourceforge.net/wp-content/uploads/2007/02/embed_flash.png&quot; alt=&quot;Macromedia Flash&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;You can post Flash content to PacerCMS.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;The ability to have Flash files display in your articles has been &quot;in the code&quot; so to speak for a while now. With this version of PacerCMS, we are finally making it available for attaching in the Media Manager. Like any other document, you must have the link to your media file handy before beginning. You can embed flash videos from a &lt;a href=&quot;http://youtube.com&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;-like service, or create your own if you have &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.adobe.com/products/flash/flashpro/&quot;&gt;Macromedia (Adobe) Flash&lt;/a&gt; available to your newsroom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking into the many options out there to manage our linked media. PacerCMS currently only supports linking to content that you have uploaded through other means, or any content that is widely available on the Web. It is &lt;a href=&quot;/index.php/development/&quot;&gt;our goal&lt;/a&gt; to integrate an upload and management script in future releases. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember, to use this feature you will &lt;a href=&quot;/index.php/download/&quot;&gt;need version 0.5 or higher&lt;/a&gt;. Have a question about using the new template engine? Just shoot an &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/pacercms-discuss&quot;&gt;e-mail to our developer community&lt;/a&gt; and we will be happy to assist.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2007 21:01:39 -0600</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Introducing the new PacerCMS Installer</title>
        <link>https://pacercms.github.io/index.php/2007/02/04/introducing-the-new-pacercms-installer/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://pacercms.github.io/index.php/2007/02/04/introducing-the-new-pacercms-installer/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: This is the second in a three part series leading up to the release of PacerCMS 0.5. You can start building for the upcoming version by &lt;a href=&quot;/index.php/download/&quot;&gt;downloading our preview release&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;float:right;margin-left:10px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://pacercms.sourceforge.net/wp-content/uploads/2007/02/new_installer.png&quot; alt=&quot;Installer&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Installation is a snap with PacerCMS 0.5.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Installers are usually the last element of an application put into place before a release. Of course, it doesn&#39;t make much sense to write a program without one. PacerCMS 0.5 introduces our first version of an install script, based heavily on the concepts presented (and in some cases, even the code base) of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://wordpress.org/&quot;&gt;WordPress blogging platform&lt;/a&gt;. While it is not quite as easy as the &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://codex.wordpress.org/Installing_WordPress&quot;&gt;Famous Five Minute Installation&lt;/a&gt;&quot;, we believe it ranks right on up there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now on to the installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Requirements&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apache or compliant Web server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PHP 4.2 or greater&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MySQL 3.23.23 or greater&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
With a bit of experience with setting up a Web application, you should be able to navigate these instructions with relative ease. If you have any questions, just drop us a line in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/pacercms-discuss &quot;&gt;PacerCMS Developers Group&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Database&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using a tool such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phpmyadmin.net/&quot;&gt;phpMyAdmin&lt;/a&gt;, create a database for your tables to reside within.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will need to know the hostname, database name, username and password for your database installation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assign read and write permissions to the user that will be accessing the database. We recommend creating a separate user account that only has permissions on this one database for security reasons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;PHP Scripts&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upload the entire contents of the package to your server root, typically an htdocs, www or public folder.
&lt;li&gt;If you have access to the command line, change the file permissions for the cache directory. (example: &lt;tt&gt;chmod 777 cache/&lt;/tt&gt;)
&lt;li&gt;You will also need write permissions on the &lt;tt&gt;./includes folder&lt;/tt&gt; if you wish to use the config file writer. (example: &lt;tt&gt;chmod 777 includes/&lt;/tt&gt;)
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Web Based Installation&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open your Web browser to http://path_to_pacercms/INSTALL/, with the CAPTIAL letters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you have already made the &lt;tt&gt;./includes&lt;/tt&gt; folder writable, you should be prompted to create the config file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete the steps provided to create the &lt;tt&gt;config.php&lt;/tt&gt; file that will reside in &lt;tt&gt;./includes&lt;/tt&gt; folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upon successful completion, you will be directed to the installer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete the steps provided to create the database structure and load the default data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be sure to write down the random password given to you, and change it to one that is easy to remember but hard to guess. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Site Settings&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Login to the Site Administration section by opening http://path_to_pacercms/siteadmin/ in your browser.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the login credentials created during the installation process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review the Settings module to add contact information for your publication.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review the Sections module to make the sections reflect the section name and editors used by your publication.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the Users module to change the password or add contact information for the site administrator.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the Users module to create login accounts for each contributor the site, using the Access sub-module to control how they interact with the Web site.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have also posted these install instructions on our documentation site should you need more detailed information. Remember, to use this feature you will &lt;a href=&quot;/index.php/download/&quot;&gt;need version 0.5 or higher&lt;/a&gt;. Have a question about using the new installer? Just shoot an &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/pacercms-discuss&quot;&gt;e-mail to our developer community&lt;/a&gt; and we will be happy to assist.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2007 00:01:22 -0600</pubDate>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
